THIS PROGRAM INCLUDES CONTENT THAT MAY BE INAPPROPRIATE FOR SOME VIEWERS.
本節目部分內容可能不適合一些觀眾
PLEASE ENJOY THE SHOW AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION.
敬請酌情觀賞
Start!
開始！
-No, thanks. -Why? It's just...
–不用，謝謝 –為什麼？只是…
DAISUKE MIYAGAWA: RANKED 2ND MOST LIKELY TO WIN
宮川大輔 排名第二最可能獲勝者
You only brought titties to thish sh-show...
你只帶胸部來上這個節目嗎？
KAZUYA KOJIMA: RANKED 7TH MOST LIKELY TO WIN
兒島一哉 排名第七最可能獲勝者
Is this how it ends?
就這樣結束了嗎？
It's sweet.
很甜
You put sugar in it, didn't you?
妳放糖了，對不對？
Oshima!
大島！
MIYUKI OSHIMA: RANKED 9TH MOST LIKELY TO WIN
大島美幸 排名第九最可能獲勝者
JIMMY ONISHI: RANKED 3RD MOST LIKELY TO WIN
吉米大西 排名第三最可能獲勝者
"See you in Yoyogi..."
“今天，在代代木…”
At 5:00 p.m.
下午5點
ATSUHIRO TSUDA: RANKED 8TH MOST LIKELY TO WIN
津田篤宏 排名第八最可能獲勝者
That's definitely him.
絕對就是他
Use those hips!
用臀部！
No!
不！
Ouch!
哎呦！
Am I injured?
我受傷了嗎？
YUKI HIMURA: RANKED THE MOST LIKELY TO WIN
日村勇紀 排名為最有可能獲勝者
Ready... Go!
預備…開始！
TOSHIFUMI FUJIMOTO: RANKED 6TH MOST LIKELY TO WIN
藤本敏史 排名第六最可能獲勝者
Old hag!
老巫婆！
TAKASHI YOSHIMURA: RANKED 5TH MOST LIKELY TO WIN
吉村崇 排名第五最可能獲勝者
You laughed, right?
你笑了，對嗎？
EIJI KOTOUGE
小峠英二
SHINJI SAITO
齋藤慎二
I got one!
我拿到了！
EIJI KOTOUGE: RANKED 4TH MOST LIKELY TO WIN
小峠英二 排名第四最可能獲勝者
That's a really tough show for the performers.
對表演者來說，這節目難度很大
Even though it's incredibly funny for the viewers.
但觀眾覺得非常好笑
As far as a plan goes,
就計劃而言
I can't spend too much time just assessing the situation.
我不能花太多時間來評估情況
That's one thing to avoid.
一定要避免
What I must do is...
我一定要做的是…
I have to go on the offensive. I have to keep making a move.
我必須繼續進攻 我必須繼續採取行動
Something showed up.
有東西出現了
KEEP MAKING A MOVE
繼續進攻
SACRIFICE YOUR BODY
犧牲你的身體
That hurts!
很痛！
God, that hurts!
天啊，痛死了！
Ten million yen, huh?
一千萬元，對吧？
This may sound strange, but I don't really care about the prize money.
這或許聽起來很怪 但我不是很在乎獎金
FORGET ABOUT THE PRIZE MONEY
無視獎金
That's not the point.
那不是重點
DOCUMENTAL: THE SHOW OF SELF-SACRIFICE
《DOCUMENTAL》 一個自我犧牲的節目
They're super-stretched.
延展性很好！
I started out as an actor.
我一開始是演員
SHINJI SAITO: RANKED THE LEAST LIKELY TO WIN
齋藤慎二 排名為最不可能獲勝者
I will create an atmosphere that only an actor can make.
我會創造一種 只有演員能創造的獨特氛圍
IS THIS THEATRICAL COMEDY?
這是戲劇中的喜劇嗎？
I'll have to make them laugh with that.
我要利用這點，令大家發笑
I'll hold back in the beginning,
我一開始會採保守攻勢
and when everyone's spent, I'll attack.
等大家的笑話都用光，我才會攻擊
That's a strategy I'll have to refine.
這是我必須精進的策略
I want to show what I'm capable of when I go for it.
我希望展現出我全力以赴的精神
IT'S TIME TO WATCH THE FINAL BOMBARDMENT
來看最後的轟擊
What a day!
真累人！
WHAT WILL UNFOLD?
將會有怎樣的發展？
Okay!
好！
IS IT COMEDY, OR VIOLENCE?
是喜劇，還是暴力？
A TRUE FIGHT TO THE DEATH
至死方休的戰鬥
That was an amazing battle.
這是一場精采的戰鬥
That's the kind of battle I wanted to see.
這正是我想看到的戰鬥
THE "BATTLE" WE ALL WANTED TO SEE
正是我們想看到的“戰鬥”
Right?
對吧？
SAITO
齋藤
VERSUS KOTOUGE
對抗小峠
It was magnificent.
太精采了
THE LEGENDARY 657 SECONDS
傳奇的657秒
This is just really funny.
這真的很好笑
This is funny!
這很好笑！
What the hell's going on at the very end?
到最後會發生什麼事？
ATTACK POINTS: SAITO = 0, KOTOUGE = 3
進攻得分 齋藤0分，小峠3分
WILL SAITO MAKE A GRAND COMEBACK?
齋藤能來一場大反擊嗎？
WILL KOTOUGE HANG ON TO WIN?
小峠能撐到最後獲勝嗎？
OR WILL IT BREAK INTO A FISTFIGHT?
或者這會成為一場拳頭之戰？
What should we do?
我們該做什麼？
What do we do?
我們要做什麼？
Restart.
再次開始
So...
那麼…
There are only 10 minutes left.
還剩十分鐘
-Let's blast on each other. -What?
–我們互相吐水吧？ –什麼？
Okay. Bring it on.
好，放馬過來
Blast on each other?
互相吐水？
-It's just you and me. -Okay, let's do it.
–只有你和我 –好，來吧
-I'll blast on you. -You will?
–我會向你吐水 –你會嗎？
I'll blast on you!
我會向你吐水
What do you mean?
你要向我吐水嗎？
You want me to blast on you? I'll blast on you.
你要我向你吐水？我就向你吐水
Ready? Bring it on.
準備好了嗎？放馬過來
That stinks!
好臭！
Who would laugh at this?
有誰覺得這個好笑？
-Bring it on! -You bring it on!
–放馬過來！ –你放馬過來！
Take that!
接招吧！
-Bring it on! -This is good.
–放馬過來！ –真不錯
Keep coming up with these.
繼續下去
Want some kimchi?
你要泡菜嗎？
-Do you want some kimchi? -Bring it on!
–你要泡菜嗎？ –來啊！
I'll give you some kimchi!
我就給你一些泡菜！
Take this!
接招吧！
What a day!
真累人！
-I'll give you kimchi. -Looking good.
–我給你泡菜 –看起來不錯
Ready?
準備好了嗎？
Take that!
接招吧！
Wow!
哇！
Come on.
來啊
This is crazy.
這真是瘋狂
Looking good.
看來不錯
-Bring it on, asshole. -I will, asshole.
–來啊，混蛋 –我會的，混蛋
Watch out.
看好了
Hey!
嘿！
See?
看到沒？
Saito, you asshole.
齋藤，你這個混蛋
What's your problem?
你有什麼問題？
-What's your problem?
–你有什麼問題？
You think you're hot since you won King of Conte?
你以為你是短篇之王就很夯嗎？
Then do something! Give me all you've got!
那就來吧！使出你的渾身解數！
-I already gave all I have! -Asshole.
–我會使出我的全部本領！ –混蛋
You think you're hot?
你以為你很夯嗎？
You have plenty of money! Let me win!
你已經有很多錢了！讓我贏！
It's not about the money!
這個跟錢無關！
It's about the money! I want 10 million yen!
當然和錢有關！我要一千萬元！
-That doesn't matter. -It does matter!
–這不重要 –這很重要！
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
You idiot!
你是白痴！
Don't waste food like that!
別這樣浪費食物！
Shut up. It's none of your...
閉嘴，這不關你的…
I can eat them, too.
我也可以吃這個
This is ridiculous.
這太荒唐了
-What idiots. -Bring it on, asshole!
–真是白癡 –來啊，混蛋！
-Eh? -Huh?
–呃？ –咦？
You asshole! Dammit!
你這個混蛋！該死的！
-What are you going to do? -Damn!
–你想做什麼？ –該死
Huh?
咦？
Damn it.
該死的
What will you do next, Saito?
齋藤，你下一步想做什麼？
-Eh? -Huh?
–呃？ –咦？
We only have...
我們只有…
There isn't any more time!
沒有時間了！
-I don't know what to do! -What will you do, asshole?
–我不知道要做什麼！ –混蛋，你想做什麼？
Why did I make it this far?
我為什麼能堅持到現在？
You survived because you were funny!
你堅持到現在是因為你很好笑！
-I wasn't funny! -If you're still here, you're funny!
–我不好笑！ –如果你還在這裡，你就是好笑！
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Yeah...
對…
-Hey! -What?
–嘿！ –怎麼了？
-What will you do? -What will you do, asshole?
–你想做什麼？ –你想做什麼，混蛋？
That won't work either!
這招沒用了！
What's with you?
你有什麼毛病？
Shut up, asshole.
閉嘴，混蛋
Saito...
齋藤…
Help me out.
幫幫我
Hey. I don't have anything left.
我的招數都用光了
We can keep circling around like this, but there's nothing left to find.
我們可以一直這樣轉圈 但已經沒有笑料了
Shut up. I know, asshole!
閉嘴，我知道，混蛋！
-I know already. -What should we do?
–我早就知道了 –我們該怎麼做？
Huh?
咦？
What is with you?
你有什麼問題？
That was a nice move.
真是不錯的一招
Saito.
齋藤
-Saito! -What?
–齋藤！ –怎樣？
Watch this.
你看
That was a nice move.
真是不錯的一招
What's your problem, asshole?
你有什麼問題，混蛋？
-Damn you. -Do you want a fight, asshole?
–你去死 –混蛋，你想打架嗎？
Look.
看好了
-Look! -What?
–看好了 –什麼？
See this?
看到沒？
-So what, asshole? -Huh?
–你在做什麼？ –什麼？
I said, "So what?"
我說：“那又怎樣”？
You're going to lose, Saito.
齋藤，你要輸了
It's all her fault!
這全是她的錯！
Old hag!
老巫婆！
-Old hag!
–老巫婆！
This is all the old hag's fault!
這全是老巫婆的錯！
Dirty old hag!
骯髒的老巫婆！
-What will you do, Saito? -Huh?
–你想做什麼，齋藤？ –咦？
Just hurry up and lose, asshole!
混蛋，你快點輸吧！
-No, asshole. -Asshole!
–不要，混蛋 –混蛋！
Huh?
咦？
-What is it, asshole? -What?
–混蛋，那是什麼？ –什麼？
-What's what?
–什麼是什麼？
What's what, asshole?
混蛋，什麼是什麼？
-Right? -Huh?
–對嗎？ –咦？
Huh?
嗯？
Look, dammit.
你看，該死的
Uh-oh.
咦
Oh, okay.
噢，好
That is gross.
很噁心耶
What are you going to do, Saito, you asshole?
齋藤，你這個混蛋，你想做什麼？
That was gross.
那很噁心耶
-Bring it on! -There's only five minutes left!
–放馬過來！ –剩下五分鐘！
-Come on, asshole! -Come get some, Kotouge!
–來吧，混蛋！ –小峠，看我的厲害！
What the hell are you?
你到底是什麼東西？
-Eh? -Huh?
–呃？ –咦？
What will you do?
你想做什麼？
-Your balls... -That prop is in the way.
–你的蛋蛋… –道具擋住了
Your balls are... Balls? Should we smack our dicks with that bat?
你的蛋蛋…蛋蛋？ 我們來用棒子打老二好嗎？
My balls. Look at them!
你看我的蛋蛋！
-Balls... -It's winter. They shrunk!
–蛋蛋… –現在是冬天，它們縮水了！
We've come this far.
我們到了這個地步
Damn.
該死
-What will you do? -Eh?
–你想怎麼做？ –呃？
Huh?
什麼？
What is it?
這是什麼？
Damn. It won't break.
該死的，打不爛
This is all...
這些都…
Hey!
嘿！
Don't waste good food!
別浪費好食物！
You're right. We'll receive complaints.
你說得對，我們會被投訴
That's it. The show's canceled.
就這樣吧，節目取消了
The controversy will end the show.
輿論會終結這個節目
And what about this?
這個呢？
The staff have to clean it up.
其他職員必須清理這些
-We have to... Hey! -Huh?
–我們必須…嘿！ –什麼？
-Saito, you asshole! -What, asshole?
–齋藤！你這個混蛋！ –什麼，混蛋？
-Ah! -Oh!
–啊！ –噢！
What will you do, asshole?
混蛋，你想怎樣？
-Eh? -Huh?
–咦？ –什麼？
-Want to split the prize money? -Eh?
–要對分獎金嗎？
I'd never split the prize money with you, asshole!
混蛋，我才不要跟你對分獎金！
-There's nothing left to use. -What should we do?
–沒什麼可以用了 –我們該怎麼辦？
What is this?
這是怎樣？
Eh?
嗯？
Huh?
什麼？
What will you do?
你要做什麼？
Hey!
嘿！
What will you do about this?
你要用這個做什麼？
-What will you do? -What will you do, asshole?
–你想怎麼樣？ –混蛋，你想用這個做什麼？
-Huh? -Yeah!
–嗯？ –什麼？
Well?
怎樣？
Hey! Look properly!
嘿！看清楚！
Hey!
嘿！
-Hey! -Ah!
–嘿！ –啊！
-You're doing good. -I'm doing good?
–你做得很好 –我做得很好？
How can this be good?
這怎麼會好？
-Take this!
–接招！
Mine is moaning louder than yours!
我的叫得比你的更大聲！
How's that?
這樣如何？
Take that, you asshole.
接招吧，你這個混蛋
The chicken is squawking.
那隻雞在叫
That was funny.
真好笑
Saito was close just now.
齋藤現在有麻煩了
-Can you still do this? -I can. Bring it on. I'm still going!
–你還可以嗎？ –我可以，放馬過來，我還行！
-Then come on, asshole! -Laugh, asshole!
–來吧，混蛋！ –笑吧，混蛋！
Watch this!
你看！
That's the thing with Saito.
齋藤就是這樣
Why didn't he bring out this side of himself earlier?
他怎麼不早點表現出這一面？
It won't squawk.
它不會叫了
I need something else.
我要別的東西
Look here!
看這裡！
You won't fit.
你塞不進去
You won't fit!
你塞不進去！
Oh, Saito...
齋藤…
That was a good choice.
那是不錯的選擇
It really was. Props that make sounds are good.
真的不錯，會叫的道具真不錯
This is good. It's really funny.
這很棒，真的很好笑
Right?
對吧？
It's really funny.
這真的很好笑
They're doing well. Really well.
他們做得很好，真得很好
What to use?
想用嗎？
Isn't there anything left?
沒東西了嗎？
Joyman is in a standoff with Joyman.
快樂人對峙快樂人
This is just really funny.
這真的很好笑
This is funny!
這很好笑！
What the hell's going on at the very end?
到最後會發生什麼事？
The "battle for comedians" is being fought by third parties.
這場諧星之戰有三方參加
I know what you mean.
我懂你的意思
I had no idea it was so...
我完全不知道那是…
They're saying something. What are they talking about?
他們在說話，他們在說什麼？
But why?
但是為什麼？
You know, honey. We're just too... What should we do?
你知道，親愛的，我們太… 我們該怎麼做？
-Thirty seconds. -Thirty seconds?
–還有30秒 –還有30秒？
Thirty seconds...
30秒鐘…
Time for one more.
還有時間來一回合
It has to be...
一定要是…
This really is quite funny.
這真的非常好笑
Wait, wait, wait. Please...
等一下，拜託…
It's over.
結束了
Kotouge is the winner!
小峠贏了！
Yes!
耶！
I did it!
我做到了！
Wow!
哇！
Is this for real?
這是真的嗎？
Well!
對啦！
Saito.
齋藤
That was amazing.
太棒了
That last battle of yours was amazing.
你們之間的最後一戰很棒
-Really? -Thank you.
–真的嗎？ –謝謝你
It was incredibly funny.
不可思議的好笑
-All right! -Good job!
–好耶！ –做得好！
We did it!
我們做到了！
Wow!
哇！
That was really funny.
那真的很好笑
That last battle was really funny.
最後一戰真的非常好笑
-Really? -Incredibly funny.
–真的嗎？ –難以置信
Thank God!
謝天謝地！
Seriously?
真的嗎？
It's a shame Saito tapped into his full power a little too late.
齋藤太晚才拿出全部的功力真是可惜
Sorry.
對不起
Seriously?
真的嗎？
That was amazing.
很精采
I think that will go down in comedic history.
我認為這會進入喜劇歷史
-Seriously? -Yeah.
–真的嗎？ –是的
We did it!
我們做到了！
We did it.
我們做到了
Wow.
哇
-Brilliant. -We did it!
–厲害 –我們做到了！
I did it!
我做到了！
I'm so happy!
我很高興！
It's over. Finally.
終於結束了
That was an amazing finale.
最後一戰非常過癮
That was amazing, wasn't it?
很精采吧，不是嗎？
Some time has passed since it ended.
這才結束了沒多久
But I don't remember a thing.
但我什麼也不記得了
Seriously.
真的
When it came down to the two of us,
等剩下我們最後兩個
it was like something suddenly switched on inside of me.
好像我身上某個開關突然打開了
It finally came, but it was too late.
這個感覺終於來了，但已經太遲了
What exactly were we doing?
我們到底在做什麼？
Was it comedy?
什麼是喜劇？
I lost track of things so badly at the end,
到最後我已經不清楚了
I couldn't even be sure it was comedy.
我甚至不能確定那是喜劇
To be honest, at the end, I was about to punch Saito in the face.
老實說，到最後 我差點一拳打在齋藤臉上
Seriously.
真的
I almost did. Seriously.
真的，我差點就這麼做了
There was madness in that comedy.
喜劇有種瘋狂的成分
I think I can say that was
我想我會說
the most intense time I've experienced in my entire life.
那是我這一生經歷過 最緊張激烈的幾分鐘
Things like this really do happen.
這樣的事情確實會發生
At the end, Saito and I used the same joke.
到最後，齋藤和我用了同樣的笑料
What are the chances of that happening?
發生這樣的事情，可能性有多大？
It must be astronomical.
幾乎不可能
In the very last few minutes,
在最後幾分鐘
we were both thinking the same thing.
我們兩個在想同樣的事情
At that moment, Saito looked into my eyes and said,
在那一刻，齋藤看著我的雙眼說
"You're my senior. Please laugh."
“你是長輩，請你笑”
But after it all ended,
但結束後
Mr. Matsumoto said we were amazing. He said we really were funny.
松本說那真的很棒 他說我們真的很好笑
That's my only consolation.
那是我唯一的安慰
Kotouge said the same thing, too. "Those words made it all worthwhile."
小峠也說了相同的話 “那些話讓我覺得一切都很值得”
That was a tough six hours.
那真是辛苦的六小時
That sure was.
的確是的
Thank you. Honestly, thank you.
真的，謝謝你
I don't want to leave yet.
我還不想走
That was an amazing battle.
那是一場精采的戰鬥
That's the kind of battle I wanted to see.
那正是我想看到的戰鬥
How can I put it?
我該怎麼說呢？
It showed what happens
你看到了
when comedians are really pushed into a corner.
諧星被逼急了會做出什麼反應
Their ability to just explode was amazing.
他們的爆發力很驚人
How should I put it? That was like sex.
我該怎麼說呢？那就像性愛
Yeah. It really was sex.
對，那就是性愛
Saito was in a position where he nearly won with just one point.
齋藤的情況 有可能只憑一分獲勝
Yeah. But he tried so hard...
對，但是他很努力…
and Saito ended up winning instead of Kotouge,
齋藤就會贏過小峠
I don't think anyone would have complained.
我想沒有人會因此抱怨
That's how great Saito was at the end.
齋藤最後的表現真的很精采
Indeed.
真的
Those two really did their best.
他們兩位都盡力而為了
I think one of them is pregnant now.
我想他們其中一人可能已經懷孕了
Seriously. I'm so glad I was with you at the end.
真的，我很高興最後能和你決戰
-Thank you. Thank you. -Good work.
–謝謝你 –做得好
-It was a pleasure.
–我很榮幸